Guide to the Paul Hurshel Sanders athletic memorabilia collection MS 614
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Paul Hurshel Sanders athletic memorabilia collection
1935-1940
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Sanders, Paul Hurshel
MS 614
3 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
This collection contains track memorabilia of Paul Hurshel Sanders. Included are several medals, trophies, track shoes, and scrapbooks of newspaper clippings.
Biographical Note
Paul Hurshel Sanders was a graduate of the Rice Institute, class of 1940. He was inducted into the Rice Athletic Hall of Fame in 1994 for his record setting achievements in track from 1935-1940. Sanders competed in multiple events consisting of 100, 220, 440, 440-relay, 880-relay, mile-relay and sprint-medley relay. His achievements included setting a new Rice and Southwest Conference record in 1937 with a time of 48.0 seconds for the 440. His sprint-medley team set a world record of 3:25.3 at the Southwest Conference in 1938.
After graduating from Rice, Sanders worked for the Shell Oil Company until his retirement in 1977. After retiring he started his own business, Sanders Accounting, Inc.
Scope and Contents Note
This collection contains track memorabila of Paul Hurshel Sanders. Included are several medals, trophies, track shoes, Rice sweater, athletic letters, batons, and scrapbooks of newspaper clippings. The memoriablia includes medals from track events Sanders won during high school and college. Among these medals are several from the Drake Relay, Southwest Athletic Conference, Oklahoma State Interscholastic, and Texas Relay.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition Note
Paul H. Sanders donated the collection in August, 2012.
Arrangement Note
The materials in this collection have been arranged in 2 series as follows: Series 1: Memorabilia Series 2: Oversize memorabilia
Index Terms
Subjects
Sports; Athletics; Universities and colleges
Document Types
photographs; programs (documents); clippings (information artifacts); awards
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University -- history.
- Series I: Memorabilia, 172504
  - Athletic Letters - Central High School, 172505 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Athletic Letters - Rice, 172506 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Athletic Pass, 172507 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Awards, 172508 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Graduation Card, 172510 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - High School Graduation, 172511 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Medallion - Drake Relay 1939, 172512 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Medals - Gold Shoes, 172525 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Name Tag, 172513 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 172514 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photos, 172515 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Programs, 172516 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Prospectus, 172517 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Receipts, 172518 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Tenth Texas Relays Ticket Stub 1937, 172526 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Transcript, 172519 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Track Numbers, 172520 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Track Stickers, 172521 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Watches, 172522 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Series II: Oversize, 172523
  - Medals Tray, 172527 (Box 2, Tray 1)
    General
    Medals date from 1933-1935, some without dates. There are multiple medals from the following: Murray State School of Agriculture Oklahoma State Interscholastic Meet University of Oklahoma Meet OBU Relays Oklahoma SWC OCU Meet Central States Interscholastic Track and Field Meet Oklahoma City Schools Athletic Award
  - Medals Tray, 172528 (Box 3, Tray 1)
    Medals date from 1937-1939. Some do not have dates. There are multiple medals from the following: Southern Athletic Conference Drake Relay Amateur Athletic Union of the United States Texas Relay Border Olympics
  - Track Shoes, 172529 (Box 2, Item 1)
  - Rice Sweater 1939, 172530 (Box 2, Item 2)
  - Running Shorts - Red, 172531 (Box 2, Item 3)
  - Trophy - New Orleans Mid-Winter Sports Assn. 1937, 172532 (Box 3, Item 1)
  - Trophy - Bison Relay, 172533 (Box 3, Item 2)
  - Batons (4), 172534 (Box 3, Item 3)
  - Slide Rule, 172535 (Box 4, Item 1)
  - High School Yearbook 1935, 172536 (Box 4, Item 2)
  - Scrapbook, 172537 (Box 4, Item 3)
  - Scrapbook, 172538 (Box 4, Item 4)
  - Items from the scrapbook, 172539 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Athletic Hall of Fame Award, 172540 (Box 4, Folder 2)